[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
Subtitles by explosiveskull
[ ALARM BUZZING DISTANTLY ]
MAN : Lights out !
[ MACHINERY GROANING ]
REPORTER [ ON TV ] : ... struggle which followed the death of Lenin
Joseph Stalin prevailed .
Stalin was the new face of an old idea : Marxism .
While the Bolsheviks firmly established
their authority at home ,
the Comintern fomented revolution
throughout the world .
Communism was on the march .
Stalin was in the Kremlin .
But what of the common people ?
What of the proletariat ?
Those who fought to win a new world ?
If we look at the history ...
[ LIGHTS CRACKLING ]
They 're frying someone , Pop .
You 're on the Hades Express , mister .
Quiet .
Death is nothing to celebrate .
Don 't matter who it is .
GIRL : He just died .
His name was Wayne Fisher .
He was 32 years old , and he killed a lady with a hammer .
He had a rib eye for his last meal .
He 's been on death row at Dewbend for three years .
And his last words were , " Go to hell . "
How do you know that ?
It 's just in my head .
All right . It 's past your bedtime , children .
Go brush your teeth and go to bed , please .
REPORTER [ ON TV ] : And history always repeats , my friends .
The ghosts of their past will soon become our present
if we do not confront them head-on .
Elise , I thought I told you to put all these toys away .
You 're not listening to me .
It wasn 't me who made this mess .
Then who was it ?
Christian , shut the door , please .
You can tell me .
It was the little boy .
He lived here a long time ago ,
and he loves playing with our toys .
- I swear . - I believe you .
I do .
You know , you 've been blessed with a gift .
You 're special .
Some people are afraid of special people .
Your daddy , he 's one of them .
He doesn 't understand your gift .
You just keep it between us from now on , okay ?
Okay .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
It 's time for bed .
Good night .
CHRISTIAN : Don 't turn off the light , Mom .
I 'm gonna be right out there , honey .
And if you ever get scared , what do you do ?
That 's right .
I gave you this , so that if you ever get scared ,
you can go ...
[ BLOWS WHISTLE THREE TIMES ]
Wherever I am , I 'll come running .
But you gotta save it for when you really need me , okay ?
Okay .
I love you both so much .
- CHRISTIAN : Love you too , Mommy . - ELISE : Love you , Mommy .
REPORTER [ ON TV ] : We see an actual atomic bombing run .
Heading for the target is Bockscar ,
code name for the ship . The radio navigator ...
ELISE : Hey .
CHRISTIAN [ WHISPERING ] : What ?
[ WHISPERING ] You asleep yet ?
CHRISTIAN : No .
Do you ever think about the people
who go to the electric chair ?
CHRISTIAN : Sometimes .
Do you wonder where they go after it 's done ?
CHRISTIAN : No . I know where they go .
Oh , yeah ?
Where ?
[ BED CREAKING ]
CHRISTIAN : They go into the dark .
ELISE [ IN NORMAL VOICE ] : Christian ?
[ WOOD CREAKING ]
[ PANTING SOFTLY ]
CHRISTIAN : What are you doing ?
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ BOY LAUGHING ]
[ FLOOR CREAKS ]
Elise .
[ SOFT CREAKING ]
You made all the mess , didn 't you ?
BOY [ WHISPERING ] : Yes .
[ CHRISTIAN BREATHING HEAVILY ]
Where 's my whistle ?
The boy is in the closet .
It 's okay .
We won 't hurt you .
Come on out .
Stop it , Elise .
BOY : I 'm not in the closet .
- [ WHISTLE BLOWS ] - [ SCREAMS ]
MAN [ ON TV ] : The people took their revenge .
Gerald . Gerald , no .
GERALD : What have you done , Elise ?
Huh ? Put your hands on the wall .
- Gerald , leave her alone ... - Quiet , Audrey !
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
[ WHISPERS ] Did you see a ghost ?
Gerald , stop it .
Yes .
I don 't want to hurt you , girl .
Just say no . That 's all you have to do .
I 'm just gonna ask you again .
Did you see a ghost ?
Yes , I did .
They 're all around us in this house .
They 're everywhere .
AUDREY : You don 't have to do this . Please .
She 's just a little girl , Gerald . Please .
No . No , Daddy .
No , no .
[ SCREAMING ]
No , no , no . Take me . Please take me .
ELISE : Help me .
Please , please , please . Gerald , stop !
Please , honey , she 's had enough .
[ LOUDLY ] Don 't ! Stop .
Please don 't . No .
Don 't tell me how to punish her , Audrey .
I punish people for a living .
ELISE : Please !
Please , not in there .
No , no , no .
No , Daddy !
No . Daddy , please , I don 't wanna go in there !
No , not in there .
No , Daddy , please , not in there !
Daddy , let me out ! Daddy , please !
You can either follow my rules ,
and sleep under my roof ,
or you can break them , and sleep under my floor .
Don 't put me in here , Daddy . Daddy , please .
Daddy , come back . I don 't wanna be in here alone .
Daddy , please !
[ CRYING ]
[ STAIRS CREAKING ]
[ CRANK GRINDING ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
- [ CRANK GRINDING ] - [ ELECTRICITY ZAPS ]
[ MACHINERY RUMBLING ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ MACHINERY CLANGS ]
[ RUMBLING STOPS ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
GIRL : Are you scared of the dark ?
ELISE : Who is that ? Who 's there ?
[ GIRL LAUGHS ]
GIRL : Don 't be afraid .
I can make it light .
ELISE : Who is that ?
GIRL : Why are you down here ?
ELISE : My daddy put me down here .
GIRL : Your daddy doesn 't treat you right .
Open this door .
There 'll be lots of light .
Go on . Open it .
There 's a key hanging up right there .
Take your time . I can wait .
You 're the only one that can open the door .
You are more powerful than you know .
I want you to help me open all the doors .
- [ KEY CLINKS ON FLOOR ] - [ GASPS ]
[ DOOR CREAKING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ RATTLING ]
REPORTER [ ON TV ] : Don 't forget what Bill the turtle just did , everyone ,
because we might have to do the same thing .
That 's what this is all about , my friends .
Duck and cover .
This is an official civil defense film
produced in cooperation with the Federal Civil ...
[ BOTTLES RATTLING ]
AUDREY : Elise ?
[ MACHINERY SNAPS , RUMBLES ]
[ REPORTER TALKING INDISTINCTLY ]
Elise ?
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ GASPING , CHOKING ]
GERALD : Audrey ?
Audrey .
Audrey !
No , no , Audrey . Audrey , no .
No . No . No .
No , Audrey !
I 'm sorry .
No !
[ SCREAMING ] No !
[ CRIES , PANTING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ SIGHS ]
ELISE : Good morning .
The dreams are coming back , Warren .
Just won 't go away , will it ?
How would you like breakfast in bed ?
- [ WARREN WHINES ] - I thought so .
You 're getting old , little Warren . We both are .
I 've been studying last week 's footage from the church basement
and we missed something . There is movement in the frame .
- SPECS : Look , right there . - ELISE : It 's a piece of lint .
SPECS : Lint doesn 't walk across the room .
Behold . The reason I was up all night .
- The lights . - [ ELECTRICITY WHINES ]
[ CHUCKLES ] That 's right , my friends . It 's voice activated .
No more dealing with those pesky switches ,
having to find them in the dark ,
straining fingers as you switch them .
Yeah , that was a real problem before , you know .
Toil in the darkness of sarcasm , my friend .
I prefer to work in the lights .
The lights ?
[ LOUDLY ] Lights !
Bad acoustics .
Natural light 's better for the environment anyway . Voilà .
I truly love that you boys are staying here in the house
But please don 't try to fix anything else
that isn 't broken .
[ CELL PHONE RINGS ]
SPECS : Spectral Sightings .
Uh , yes , she is .
Elise !
- ELISE : This is Elise . - GARZA [ ON PHONE ] : Hey there .
My name is Ted Garza .
Nice to meet you , Mr. Garza .
GARZA : Yeah . I 'm-I 'm having some problems .
Things are happening in my house ,
and they say that you know about this stuff .
I know some things .
GARZA : Yeah , well , I was wondering if you could take a look .
I need ... I need help is the thing , see .
May I ask where you live ?
GARZA : I live at 414 Appletree Road
Five Keys , New Mexico .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
Um . Mr. Garza , ahem ,
I wish I could help you , but I really can 't .
I 'm so sorry .
I thank you very much for thinking of me .
ELISE : Sorry to drag you boys out of bed .
That man who called today about a job ?
He told me he lives in the house that I grew up in .
I call it a house because it wasn 't a ... a home .
I don 't have memories from that place . I have scars .
This gift I have that you boys are so in awe of ,
my father tried to beat it out of me .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
And ...
my mother ,
she was killed in that house .
She was murdered by something that I brought into this world .
This demon wants to use my abilities ,
and it will hurt the ones I love to get to me .
That 's why I never want to go into The Further
like I did for Quinn .
I have spent my life fighting these things
because I can never forget the look
on my mother 's face when she died .
So ...
[ SNIFFS ]
I have to help this man
because I know what he 's up against .
SPECS : We 'll pack up the truck tonight .
We 'll get an early start tomorrow .
Not this time .
This one , I have to do ...
alone .
[ TIRES SQUEALING ]
[ VAN RUMBLING ]
[ BRAKES SQUEALING ]
We have to come with you now . This cost us 700 bucks .
Plus 200 for the logo paint job .
[ HORN HONKS ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ ELECTRIC LINES HUMMING SOFTLY ]
[ BRAKES SQUEAL ]
Oh . Oh ...
[ PUMPJACK CREAKING ]
[ EXHALES DEEPLY ]
ELISE : Before we go inside ,
I brought some clothes for you boys .
Some of it belonged to Jack , and it 's very important to me .
GARZA : I bet I can guess who you are .
There 's no need . I 'm Elise .
- Hi . - And this is Specs and Tucker ,
my associates .
She 's psychic .
We 're sidekick .
Where 's that ?
She 's psychic . We 're sidekick .
[ CHUCKLES ]
Sorry , I 'm ... I 'm not understanding .
Yeah , never mind .
You wanna come in ? Here .
Come on . I 'm supposed to invite you in . Come on .
- Hello . - [ GRUNTS ]
[ DOOR CREAKS , CLOSES ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
REPORTER [ ON TV ] : ... and history always repeats , my friends .
The ghosts of their past will soon become our present
if we do not confront them ...
You still have so much of our old stuff .
GARZA : It was all here .
Pretty good stuff , you know ?
I didn 't see any reason to get rid of it .
There 's stories .
About your family .
I never listened to them when they said that
this wasn 't a place that I should live .
You know , I looked at it , and I just saw a little house .
I said , " Screw the stories , " and I bought it .
[ VOICES WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY ]
GARZA : Now I believe the stories .
[ VOICES CONTINUE WHISPERING ]
You getting anything ?
There are so many spirits in this house ,
it 's hard to tell the good from the evil .
A lot of people died in that prison .
When did these occurrences start ?
GARZA : Soon after I moved in .
First , it was , uh ,
the little things , you know ?
Things that ...
AUDREY : You 've been blessed with a gift .
AUDREY [ DISTORTED ] : You 're special .
You just keep it between us from now on , okay ?
[ GERALD SCREAMS ]
GERALD : No . No !
You okay ?
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
Yeah , I 'm ... I 'm fine .
These experiences you 're having ...
Where do they mainly occur ?
Mostly in one room .
I keep it locked now .
I haven 't opened it in three months .
I 'll take that one .
You wanna give me a hand ?
That 's good .
A little bit more .
[ SPECS AND GARZA PANTING ]
[ KEY CLICKS ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ CAMERA CLICKS , WHINES ]
Sorry .
Can 't go in there .
[ CAMERA CLICKS , WHINES ]
When it first started ,
I could hear somebody just walking back and forth .
Someone was talking to themselves .
You think you 're going crazy , and then you ...
you actually hear it .
And you know you 're not .
Finally , one day , I walked in ,
and I screamed at it :
" You stop .
Please stop . "
My whole life savings is in this place .
You gotta help me .
You gotta help me , please .
That 's what we do .
SPECS : The camera is so we can see
what she sees from out in the truck .
We call it the " Winneba-ghost . "
[ SNORTS ]
I think I 'm gonna go there now .
[ MACHINERY GRINDING ]
You really are gonna stay here all alone ?
My presence tends to draw the spirits out
of their dark , little corners .
You need to take this .
Thank you .
Good night .
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ MACHINERY GRINDING , CREAKING ]
SPECS : Can you hear us , Elise ?
- [ MIC SQUEALS ] - [ ELISE GRUNTS ]
Yes . Try not to drown out the other voices .
SPECS [ ON RADIO ] : We got you , we 're gone .
Here you go .
- What 's this ? - Lights .
Thanks .
[ FLOOR CREAKING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ VIDEO CRACKLING ]
[ ELISE SIGHS ]
[ LAUGHS SOFTLY ]
I thought you were gone forever .
ELISE [ ON RADIO ] : My mother got this for my brother
and he lost it when he was 6 years old .
Safe now .
Oh ...
Huh .
Mm .
[ FLOOR CREAKING ]
[ GASPS ]
[ PANTING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
- [ ELECTRICITY ZAPS ] - [ GASPS ]
[ FLOOR CREAKS ]
[ CREAKING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
TUCKER [ ON RADIO ] : Stop .
- What ? - Go back , to the left .
SPECS : What ?
Yeah , nothing .
Thought I saw some feet .
Feet ?
[ GASPS ]
Elise , there 's someone right in front of you .
SPECS [ ON RADIO ] : Looks like a woman .
ELISE : I don 't see anything .
SPECS : Elise , be careful .
[ ELISE BREATHING HEAVILY ]
ELISE : I don 't see what you 're seeing .
SPECS : You 're going to touch it .
Be careful .
Help her .
[ SCREAMS ]
Elise ? Elise ? What happened ?
The whistle .
It took the whistle .
What were you doing in there ?
Thought you were gonna stay in the bedroom .
ELISE : Something led me down there .
The spirit of a woman .
I don 't know why she said , " Help her , "
but it 's a ghost I have seen before
in this house ,
when I was 16 years old .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ SOFT SCRAPING ]
[ CLATTERING ]
Did you hear that ?
Hear what ?
There 's someone in the laundry room .
No , there isn 't .
I heard it .
I 'm gonna go look .
No . Don 't , Elise .
Hello .
I live here with my brother , Christian .
What 's your name ?
Stop it .
You 're making it up .
Come out and see my brother .
He doesn 't believe that you 're here .
GERALD : Christian !
What are you doing , girl ?
There 's someone in the laundry .
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
There 's no one in here .
You 're doing it again .
You can 't punish me for this .
I never wanted it . I never asked for it .
Sh .
If there 's one thing
you 've been doing your whole life , Elise
it 's ask for it .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ STATIC HUMMING ]
[ GASPS ]
[ CRYING ] I won 't let you hurt me anymore .
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
CHRISTIAN : Please !
Elise .
Elise !
Elise , don 't go !
GERALD : Leave her be . Leave her be .
She needs to learn that nobody else
can possibly love someone like her .
I haven 't been back here since .
I think that 's all for tonight .
We 'll pick it up tomorrow .
ELISE : Christian and I came here a lot as kids .
Do I look okay ?
Yeah , of course .
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
GIRL : All right .
[ GIGGLES ]
Oh .
[ LAUGHING ] Oh . I 'm sorry . I ...
You just look so much like someone I know very well .
GIRL : Oh , really ?
I 'm Elise .
Melissa .
Imogen .
And you 're sisters ?
Yes , we are .
Tucker .
Specs .
I 'm Specs . Or Steven .
Whatever . Your choice .
She 's psychic , and we 're sidekick .
I 'm sorry ?
Forget it .
So are you guys visiting the area ?
Tough to talk about . Actually , it 's pretty confidential .
It 's a poltergeist infestation involving Ted Garza .
Do you know him ? He lives , like , down the road or ... ?
Ghosts and ghouls .
What he 's trying to say is we 're ghost hunters .
- The three of us . - TUCKER : Kind of like cops .
Only we don 't arrest humans .
[ LAUGHS ]
I 'm funny too . A lot of the time .
- I can also be funny ... What ? - Okay . Okay .
ELISE : I think that that 's enough , boys .
Oh , yeah ?
I used to live in this town a long time ago .
Well , good for you . You got out .
Um . I 'm really making a fool out of myself . We 're making ...
No , you 're not .
It 's really nice to meet you .
MAN : Ernie , how 's it hanging ?
Dad , over here .
- How are you ? - Hot enough for you ?
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
Hello , Christian .
Have I aged that much ?
ELISE : Well , aren 't you gonna say anything ?
I have nothing to say to you .
Girls , come on . Let 's go .
- Come on . - IMOGEN : We just got here .
Hear me out .
I 'm ... I 'm still your sister , and ...
That only means something if I choose it to
mean something , and I choose it not to .
Please , Christian .
I just want you to hear my piece .
I didn 't know how this was gonna go .
I thought you could see the future .
- Is this really your sister ? - No , it isn 't ! Come on .
Yes , yes , I am his sister .
Listen to me . You listen .
Now , when we were children , you terrified me .
You scared the life out of me
with stories about a monster behind a red door ,
and then you opened the door , and you left .
You left me .
You abandoned me to a real monster , our father .
Look , I wish you no harm , but you stay away from us , Elise .
You stay away .
Christian .
[ DOOR CLOSES , BELL TINKLES ]
Christian !
[ CRYING ]
I was stupid to come back here .
No , you weren 't . You 're helping people .
That 's what you do , remember ?
Elise .
I 'm sorry .
He can be unreasonable sometimes .
Knowing what he grew up with , that 's perfectly understandable .
He 's never told us anything about his childhood .
I 've never even seen a picture .
He never told us anything about you .
I left him alone , and I shouldn 't have .
He is a great dad , you know ?
I love him a lot .
You have no idea how happy that makes me , honey .
Um .
- Tucker ? - ... share with me . Yes ?
ELISE : Do you have the still frames that we printed ?
- Yes , I do . - ELISE : Bring them here .
Eaten by the female , that 's why ...
Tucker ?
ELISE : Tucker , I need you .
- TUCKER : Yes . - Come on .
Here you go .
Here . You give this to your dad ,
and you tell him it was taken yesterday
in our old bedroom .
Oh , I think he will be very surprised to see it .
I 'm so happy to meet you .
MELISSA : Okay .
[ MACHINERY GRINDING ]
SPECS : Testing . One , two .
Can you hear me , guys ? No .
ELISE : I noticed this last night , but I couldn 't quite place it .
Then Christian reminded me that when I was a child
I saw a red door .
The entity that killed my mother came through it .
I don 't get it . A red door is a red door . Anyone can see it .
No , it 's not a literal door . It 's a metaphysical one .
Remember when I went into The Further
to find Quinn Brenner ?
I came across a red door .
And I ... I passed through it ,
and it took me deeper into The Further .
If I can find out what it means ,
I might be able to stop the thing
[ DISTORTED VOICE ] that 's haunting this house .
[ DISTORTED VOICE ] Well , this might help .
[ DEVICE BUZZES ]
I spoke to you last night .
Are you there ? Can you hear me ?
[ STATIC CRACKLING ]
You took something from me .
Why ?
ELISE : Why did you say , " Help her " ?
Help who ?
[ WHISTLE BLOWS THREE TIMES ]
[ STATIC CRACKLING ]
This way .
[ WHISTLE BLOWS THREE TIMES ]
[ TUCKER GASPS ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ FLOOR CREAKING ]
[ SQUEAKING ]
[ WHISTLE BLOWS THREE TIMES ]
[ ELISE GASPS ]
[ IN NORMAL VOICE ] Is that you ?
Whistle once for yes , twice for no .
Are you the woman I saw last night ?
[ WHISTLE BLOWS ONCE ]
Is there an entity in this house
that is trying to hurt Ted Garza ?
[ WHISTLE BLOWS ONCE ]
Are you that entity ?
[ WHISTLE BLOWS TWICE ]
Is there something you 're trying to show me ?
[ WHISTLE BLOWS ONCE ]
Is what you want to show me
behind this wall ?
[ WHISTLE BLOWS ONCE , SUSTAINED ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ ELISE GASPS ]
Keys .
Freeze , buddy . Freeze .
On .
Wait . On .
[ PANTING ]
[ CLATTERING ]
[ DOOR CREAKING ]
TUCKER : Wait .
ELISE : Thank you .
[ ELISE GASPS ]
What is it you wanna show me ?
[ SHUFFLING ]
- FEMALE GHOST : Help her ! - [ ELISE SCREAMS , GRUNTS ]
[ CHAIN RATTLING ]
Help me .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ GASPS ]
That 's not a ghost .
ELISE : Oh , my God .
[ BOTH CRYING ]
Oh , my God .
I 'll break the chain .
No , you won 't .
[ WOMAN WHIMPERING ]
GARZA : Move .
Get away from her !
I asked you , help me get rid of the ghost .
Help me get rid of it !
GARZA [ OVER HEADSET ] : Help me !
Why did you have to come down here ?
[ STATIC CRACKLES ON HEADSET ]
- Why ? - Your ghost led us down here .
He 's in my head .
[ WHISPERS ] He 's in my head .
[ GUN CLICKS ]
[ FOOTSTEPS CREAKING ]
Is that your friend ?
That is your friend .
[ LOCK CLICKS ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ PANTS ]
[ FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING SLOWLY ]
You there , Specs ?
Specs !
[ PANTING ]
What ?
[ OBJECT CLATTERS DISTANTLY ]
[ PANTING ]
- [ GRUNTS ] - [ GUN FIRES ]
[ GRUNTS ]
- [ OBJECTS CLATTER ] - Fuck .
[ CLICKING RHYTHMICALLY ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ SPECS GRUNTS ]
[ SIGHS , THEN PANTS ]
[ MAN CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY OVER POLICE RADIO ]
WHITFIELD : Her name is Mara Jennings .
Uh , she 's a nurse from a town about 10 miles outside of here .
She 's been missing for approximately four months .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
Watch your step down .
Can you stick around for a few days ?
Yeah , we 'll be here .
I 'm gonna have to get statements from all of you .
[ SIGHS ]
There are plenty of demons in this world
who are very much alive , and you stopped one of them .
Thanks , Elise .
[ HOUSE CREAKING ]
[ MACHINERY CREAKS ]
IMOGEN : Dad , this is crazy .
CHRISTIAN : This is something I have to do .
CHRISTIAN : I gotta find it .
It 's a little whistle , a little silver whistle .
ELISE : Look , I deal in the spirit world ,
and spirits can make people do bad things in the real world .
Some of these people come to me for help .
But to you , that 's weird .
To me , it 's a day job .
This one was different , though .
The haunted house was my house .
[ OBJECTS CLATTER ]
[ SIGHS ] It 's not in here .
Hey , I 'm gonna check on him .
Mm-hm .
Why would Garza invite you up ,
knowing the risk that you might discover Mara ?
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES FAINTLY ]
These hauntings can be terrifying things .
Maybe the fear of the beyond ...
overcame the fear of getting caught .
Mm .
Or maybe he wanted to get caught .
- [ SHRIEKS ] - [ SCREAMS ]
- [ GASPS ] - What ? What is it ?
I-I 'm sorry .
I 'm , uh , seeing things .
The shock of the whole thing , I suppose .
Do you need me for anything else ?
No .
Thank you .
CHRISTIAN : Melissa ?
Dad ?
CHRISTIAN : Down here , honey . I found the whistle .
[ FLOOR CREAKING ]
Dad ?
[ DEMON WHEEZING ]
[ SOFT TAP ]
[ PANTING QUIETLY ]
[ OBJECT TAPPING ]
[ GASPS ]
[ SCREAMS ]
[ PANTING ]
[ OBJECT THUDS ]
[ RAGGED BREATHING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ SOBBING ]
[ PANTING AND SCREAMING ]
- [ INAUDIBLE SCREAMING ] - [
FEEDBACK RINGS ]
Shh .
- CHRISTIAN : What are you doing ? - You can 't find her , can you ?
What happened to her ? Where is she ?
- We 've looked everywhere . - ELISE : Not everywhere .
[ BREATHING RAGGEDLY ]
[ CLICKS ]
CHRISTIAN : Oh , God , no .
Imogen , call an ambulance .
Now !
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
How did you know where she was ?
What happened to her ?
There 's something evil in that house ...
and I let it into this world .
I think it made Ted Garza do what he did ,
and now it has taken your sister 's spirit ,
and I 'm gonna find it , and I 'm gonna finish it tonight .
I can see things too .
When I was a little girl ...
I went to sleep and floated out of my bedroom ,
all the way to our elderly neighbor 's house .
Then she told me she was leaving this world
and going on to the next .
My dad told me she had died the night before .
I told him I already knew .
He wasn 't too happy to hear that .
Imogen , let 's go .
Come on , honey .
No , I ... I 'm staying .
Just trust me , okay ?
Come on , boys , let 's get our things
and get in the house and get started .
[ CAR DOORS SHUT ]
Son of a ...
ELISE : I am going to get the attention
of all the spirits in this house .
I need things that were important to Garza .
Specs , go upstairs .
There is a Bible he held very dear to him .
It was a red King James version , and I need you to find it .
- Take Imogen with you . - SPECS : Okay .
And do not let her out of your sight .
- SPECS : I won 't . - Tucker and I are going down
to the fallout shelter .
I get the death chamber , he gets Bible camp
with the most beautiful girl on Earth ?
- That 's not a democracy . - You 're the only one I trust
to go down there with me .
Don 't patronize me , woman .
IMOGEN : So why do you guys dress like that ?
It was Elise 's idea . She dressed us .
No , my usual style 's a lot more laid back .
It 's a little ...
- [ GASPS ] - What ?
Dude .
This is vintage . No , this is worth a lot .
I 'm serious . We gotta find this thing .
I 'm just saying .
- Gotta have hobbies . - I 'm saying .
Can 't all be work .
Gotta enjoy yourself , go out on a date .
[ SCOFFS ]
You gotta do stuff like that .
There 's something here .
I can feel it .
She wants me to have it .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
Oh , that should do it .
- Step aside . - Yes , sir .
[ GRUNTS ]
[ GRUNTING ]
[ GASPS ]
[ SIGHS ]
[ FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING ]
It 's time to sleep .
[ WOMAN SOBBING ]
I know this slip .
- This will help you sleep . - Don 't make me drink anymore .
WOMAN : Please , let me go . I beg you .
[ SHUSHING ]
There you go .
WOMAN [ SOBBING ] : Please , let me go .
I promise I won 't tell .
Please , let me ...
[ WOMAN WAILS ]
[ PANTING ]
Did you hear that ?
YOUNG CHRISTIAN : Hear what ?
My brother doesn 't believe that you 're here .
GERALD : Christian !
There 's someone in the laundry .
There 's no one here .
YOUNG ELISE : You can 't punish me for this . I never wanted it .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
- [ GERALD GRUNTS ] - [ WOMAN WHIMPERS ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ SIGHS ]
Goodbye , Anna .
[ GASPS ]
She wasn 't dead .
My father did the exact same thing that Garza did .
The woman I saw in this house all those years ago ...
she was alive .
I could have helped her .
I let him kill her .
[ SIGHS ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ WATER DRIPPING ]
ELISE : Take this thing off .
TUCKER : Okay .
[ GRUNTS ]
[ COUGHS ]
Her death was my fault .
Until I free her from wherever he put her ...
she 's trapped in the dark .
Lost .
I 'm going in there .
Stand back .
Go for it .
I 'm good .
[ LATCH CLICKS ]
[ CASE CLATTERS ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
I 'm sorry , Anna .
I failed you .
[ SOBS ]
[ WATER DRIPPING ]
Oh , my God .
[ SCOFFS ]
Wait , wait , wait , wa ...
Where you going ?
TUCKER : Elise .
[ HUSHED ] Elise .
Elise .
You weren 't the only one , Anna .
[ OBJECT CLANKS ]
[ RUSTLING ]
[ CASES SCRAPING ]
[ GROANS ]
[ DEMON BREATHES RAGGEDLY ]
[ OBJECT CLANKS ]
- [ GROWLS ] - [ SCREAMING ]
- GERALD : Audrey ! - Elise ?
GERALD : Audrey .
Audrey .
Elise .
Where am I ?
You 're in a special place ...
where the spirits go .
Who are you ?
I 'm ... A friend .
I don 't wanna be here .
I don 't wanna go where the spirits go .
Elise ...
no matter what your daddy says ...
you have to go on doing what you do .
Never be afraid of your ability .
Daddy doesn 't mean it when he yells at me .
He 's scared ...
of the man with the keys .
He 's the one controlling it all .
He 's the one who opens all the doors .
- He opens all the red doors ? - Yes .
The man with the keys said I 'm more powerful than I know .
He says he wants me to help him open every door .
He says he 'll do anything it takes to get me .
He 's standing right behind you .
- [ DEMON BREATHES RAGGEDLY ] - GERALD : No !
[ GAGS ] Leave this place !
[ GRUNTS ]
Elise , wake up .
Elise !
[ YELLS ] Specs !
TUCKER : I need help !
- Here . Careful with her head . - Go , go , go .
She 's on the other side .
- Somebody has to go in and help . - Yeah ,
who 's gonna do that ? I can 't do that , can you do that ?
- I didn 't say ... - I can do it .
I can help her .
I 've never actually hypnotized anybody before .
I 've never been hypnotized .
Well , then you won 't know what I 'm doing wrong , right ?
Okay , um ...
The exercise , it 's a little ...
I 'm gonna ... I 'll put my finger there .
[ CHUCKLES ] E.T.
[ IMITATING E.T. ] Imogen .
[ IN NORMAL VOICE ] That 's pretty cool .
- Just look here . - Mm-hm .
And , uh , concentrate on it and just relax .
Imagine that your body is made of water
and you 're in the ocean .
That doesn 't make sense .
- What ? - She 's made of water ...
and she 's in the ocean . Therefore , she is the ocean .
Would you like to do this ?
- TUCKER : Thank you . - SPECS : I 'll still be here .
- Don 't touch the subject . - SPECS : I 'm not .
Move away .
[ TICKING RHYTHMICALLY ]
Close your eyes .
- [ SIGHS ] - Listen to the ticking .
Focus on it .
I 'm going to count back from five .
By the time I reach one , you will be hypnotized .
Five , four ...
three , two , one .
Nod if you can hear me .
When I say " now , " you will open your eyes ,
[ VOICE FADES ] and you will be on the other side .
TUCKER [ SOFTLY ] : Now .
VOICE [ WHISPERS ] : Wanna go there .
[ GASPS ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
I 'll help you .
[ DOOR CREAKS ]
[ EERIE VOICES MOANING ]
[ DOG GROWLS , THEN BARKS ]
Red door .
SPECS : That 's the red door Elise was talking about .
ANNA : This is the place .
[ RUMBLING ]
[ DOOR CREAKS ]
[ EERIE WHISPERING CONTINUES ]
[ VOICES YELLING INDISTINCTLY ]
ANNA : I can 't go in there .
If he finds me , he 'll ...
He 'll take me again .
Trust me . You 'll find what you 're looking for in there .
VOICE 1 : Please !
I admit it !
VOICE 2 : Shut up !
VOICE 3 : That 's right !
IMOGEN : Elise ?
VOICE 3 : The key is missing .
VOICE 4 : You 're all gonna get it again !
[ GASPS ]
[ VOICE LAUGHS ]
YOUNG ELISE : Do you ever think about the people
who go to the electric chair ?
YOUNG CHRISTIAN : Sometimes .
YOUNG ELISE : Do you wonder where they go ?
VOICE : Your turn now .
[ ELISE WHIMPERING ]
[ VOICE LAUGHS ]
[ ELISE SOBS ]
[ OBJECT CLANKS ]
[ VOICE LAUGHS ]
[ VOICES WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY ]
[ GASPS ]
[ RATTLING ]
VOICE : Look out !
[ VOICES YELLING INDISTINCTLY ]
[ FEMALE VOICES SCREAMING ]
- [ CLINKING ] - [ ELECTRIC CRACKLES ]
[ MONITOR BEEPING ]
[ DEMON BREATHES RAGGEDLY ]
[ WHIMPERS ]
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
REPORTER [ ON TV ] : ... always repeats , my friends . The ghosts of their past ...
[ GASPS ]
REPORTER [ ON TV ] : ... if we do not confront them head-on .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ DOOR CREAKS ]
GERALD : If there 's one thing you 've been doing your whole life ,
Elise , it 's ask for it .
No ! No , Daddy !
[ CANE STRIKES ]
[ GROANS ] They 're all around us in this house .
Everywhere .
[ SCREAMING ]
[ CRIES OUT ]
She needs to learn nobody else
can possibly love someone like her .
[ SOBBING ] Stop , Daddy , stop .
- YOUNG ELISE : No , Daddy , please . - Please , stop . No .
- Stop . - YOUNG ELISE : No . No .
[ FADING ] No , Daddy !
AUDREY [ DISTORTED ] : Some people are afraid of special people .
Your daddy is one of them .
TEENAGE ELISE : I won 't let you hurt me anymore .
[ DEMON BREATHES RAGGEDLY ]
GERALD : Did you see a ghost ?
Just say no . That 's all you have to do .
TEENAGE ELISE : You can 't punish me for this . I never wanted it .
I never asked for it .
You killed your mother .
[ VOICES YELLING INDISTINCTLY ]
[ BREATHES RAGGEDLY ]
- [ CANE THWACKS ] - [ ELISE GRUNTS ]
Elise .
Elise !
[ BREATHES RAGGEDLY ]
GARZA : He 's in my head . He 's in my head .
ELISE : My father did the exact same thing as Garza .
My father was your puppet .
I am not gonna feed you
with hatred anymore , demon .
You can fucking starve .
[ GROWLS ]
IMOGEN : Elise !
ELISE : No !
[ SCREAMS ]
Leave her alone !
You wanna take somebody , take me .
[ CHAINS RATTLING ]
[ MELISSA IMOGEN GROANING ]
[ VOICES WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY ]
Let them go .
FEMALE VOICE : See now ?
[ SCREAMS ]
[ VOICES SCREAMING ]
- [ SCREAMING ] - [ MONITOR BEEPING ]
Honey ? Honey ?
Nurse ! Nurse , get in here !
Melissa !
[ GROWLS ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ GRUNTS AND SCREAMS ]
[ HEART MONITOR FLAT LINES ]
- [ DOCTORS CHATTER INDISTINCTLY ] - One , two , three , four ...
[ SHRIEKS ]
- [ DEMON GROWLS ] - [ GRUNTS ]
[ VOICE WAILING ]
I 'm sorry .
[ GASPS ]
[ ROARS ]
No ! No !
No !
[ INAUDIBLE SCREAMS ]
[ BREATHING RAGGEDLY ]
IMOGEN : Elise !
[ SCREECHES ]
[ RUMBLING ]
[ WHISTLE BLOWS ]
[ WHISTLE ECHOING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
Hands off my little girl .
- [ DEMON GROWLS ] - [ YELLS ]
[ SHACKLE CLINKS ]
No , no , no .
IMOGEN : Elise !
She 's hurt .
[ PANTS AND GROANS ]
[ THUNDER RUMBLES ]
[ DOOR CREAKS ]
[ WHIMPERS AND SNIFFLES ]
[ SNIFFS ]
[ HEART MONITOR FLAT LINING ]
Return to your body . Go .
[ GASPS ]
Baby .
Oh , Dad .
Elise , she saved me .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
I don 't know the words .
I already know , my love .
[ SOBS ]
Keep helping people .
Go home .
- Imogen , wake up ! - [ GASPS ]
Are you okay ?
Yeah , I think so .
[ GASPS , THEN PANTS ]
You can 't get rid of me that easy . The hospital .
WOMAN [ ON PA ] : Nurse needed in ICU stat .
Nurse needed in ICU stat .
Hey , sweetheart .
- IMOGEN : Hey . - Hi ,
I 'm okay .
Oh , my God .
- IMOGEN : Hi . - MELISSA : Mm .
[ SIGHS ]
I believe this is yours .
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
You were right , Christian .
I 'm cursed .
Demons follow me around .
But I don 't wanna give them
what they want for one second longer .
Fear and pain is what feeds them .
I 'm the one that 's been feeding them ...
shutting you out all these years .
You forgive me ?
I never should have left you .
[ SIGHS ]
Thank you .
Yes .
[ STAMMERS ] Oh ...
Melissa ...
you gonna eat that ?
Go for it .
You know , I always thought that I was afraid of dying ...
but now I realize that I wasn 't .
I was afraid of dying ...
before I truly had a family again .
Hm .
Now I do .
Son of a ...
I told you not to park there .
- Just saying , I did . - Listen to your buddy .
He gets the girl , I get the ticket ?
[ LAUGHS ]
ELISE : I 'm riding shotgun .
SPECS : We 'll have to come back here to deal with that ticket .
[ ENGINE STARTS ]
[ THUNDER RUMBLES ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ GASPS SOFTLY ]
[ TICKING ]
Dalton .
Today was just so horrible .
I 'm scared nothing 's gonna change .
It will .
I promise you .
JOSH : Just gotta give it time .
[ CLOCK CONTINUES TICKING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ GASPS ] Oh , Dalton .
[ PHONE RINGING ]
[ PHONE BEEPS ]
Hello .
LORRAINE [ ON PHONE ] : I 'm so sorry for calling so late . My name is Lorraine .
You helped my family a long time ago ,
when my son was just a boy .
And now the same thing is happening to my grandson .
Dalton .
LORRAINE : How did you know his name ?
It 's what I do .
Tell Josh I 'll be there in the morning .
LORRAINE : Thank you .
- Good night . - LORRAINE : Good night .
[ PHONE BEEPS ]
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]
[ METRONOME TICKING ]
Subtitles by explosiveskull
[ ♪ ♪ ♪ ]